Berkley Olmstead

5531 S. Adonis, Boise, ID 83716 | 208-871-3882 olms2074@gmail.com | www.berklevolmstead.com | github.com/Bolmstead

Summary

Full-Stack software developer with experience creating Full-Stack web applications, REST API's, and backend logic to communicate with SQL and MongoDB databases. Currently working as a Full-Stack developer building a CRM website application to be adopted for internal use by several trucking companies.

Skills

Languages, Frameworks, and Libraries: Javascript, Python, React, Redux, Node.JS, Node Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, SQL, Sequelize, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Less.JS, Node-pg, Flask, SQLAlchemy, AJAX, Axios, Material-UI, Ant Design, Bootstrap

Other Tools: DOM manipulation, Netlify & Heroku deployment, Git, Github, APIs using JSON or XML, Database Schema Design, Event-Driven Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Web-scraping

Experience

TEKware - Boise, ID (remote position)

August 2021 - Present

Software Developer

- Built a homepage dashboard UI for trucking company managers to create/edit/delete tasks for their employees, and for the employees to view and complete these tasks.
- Created the API routes and backend models creating many to many relationships enabling managers to assign and unassign their truck drivers to their specific trailers and tractors.
- Developed the dynamic UI for managers to create, edit, and delete these trailer and tractor assignments.
- Utilized and refined my skills in the following technologies for this project: React, Redux, Node.JS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML, CSS, Less.JS, Ant Design, Git, and Github.

Idaho State Tax Commission - Boise, ID

February 2016 - March 2020

Tax Auditor

- Investigated non-filing taxpayer income and tax documents to decide their domicile status.
- Calculated state individual tax deficiencies and prepared audit findings defending my position.
- Handled over 200 audits simultaneously, increasing the state's income by over \$80,000 a year on average.
- Met with taxpayers to communicate tax code ambiguities guiding them to an appropriate plan of action.

Projects

FreeBay Website

February 2021 - Present

- Developed a full-stack product bidding website using React, HTML, CSS, and Axios.
- Built the <u>backend and API</u> with Node.JS, Node-PG, and Express that contains routes that supplies a JWT upon validation, provides queried product data, posts bids, and updates any bids if a product is won.
- Created database schema with multiple relational tables and deployed the API with Heroku.
- Utilized the Material-UI React CSS framework to create a dynamic, mobile responsive user interface.

Education

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track

Completion Date: April 2021

- 800+ hours of hands-on online course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects.
- Refined skills in front-end and back-end web development, databases, and data structures & algorithms.

University of Idaho- College of Business and Economics - Moscow, ID

Degrees Received: December 2012

B.S. in Business, Accounting and Finance - Cumulative GPA: 3.45

Certified Public Accountant Exam - Passed all 4 sections of exam